https://www.apcointl.org/privacy-policy-data-usage/

APCO International Privacy Policy for Data Usage | APCO International
Skip to content
FacebookTwitterLinkedinFlickr
Search for:
Log In
MenuAboutAPCO LeadershipExecutive CommitteeExecutive CouncilPast PresidentsContact APCOVoteAPCO HistoryOnline MuseumSubmit an ItemNewsroomAPCO Fact SheetPress KitPhotos9-1-1 Public Information and EducationAPCO ProjectsAnnual ReportAPCO StoreGovernanceAPCO Governing DocumentsAPCO Board of DirectorsAPCO Executive CouncilAPCO Membership QuorumAPCO as a Global LeaderAffiliates and International Chapters CloseGovt RelationsTopics4.9 GHz6 GHz9-1-19-1-1 Location AccuracyFirstNetIP TransitionMobile AppsSOC RevisionResource LibraryFCC RulesFCC ProceedingsFederal LegislationAPCO PartnersPublic FilingsFCC FilingsFederal CourtCongressional TestimonyAdministrationMeet the TeamGovernment Relations NewsTabletopX Blog CloseTraining & CertificationDisciplinesPublic Safety Telecommunicator (PST)Public Safety Telecommunicator (PST), 7th EditionPublic Safety Telecommunicator (PST), 7th Edition, CanadaTelecomunicador de Seguridad PúblicaPublic Safety Telecommunicator, Instructor CloseEmergency Medical Dispatch (EMD)Emergency Medical Dispatch ProgramEmergency Medical Dispatcher (EMD)Emergency Medical Dispatcher (EMD), InstructorEmergency Medical Dispatch (EMD) ConceptsEmergency Medical Dispatch (EMD) Manager CloseFire Service CommunicationsFire Service Communications (FSC)Fire Service Communications (FSC) Instructor CloseLaw Enforcement CommunicationsLaw Enforcement Communications (LEC)Law Enforcement Communications (LEC), Instructor CloseCommunications Training OfficerCommunications Training Officer CourseCommunications Training Officer (CTO) Instructor Course CloseLeadership & SupervisionCommunications Center Supervisor (CCS)Registered Public-Safety Leader (RPL)Certified Public-Safety Executive (CPE) Program CloseAgency Instructor CoursesAll CoursesLeadership ProgramsRegistered Public-Safety Leader (RPL)Registered Public-Safety Leaders CloseCertified Public-Safety Executive (CPE) ProgramCertified Public-Safety Executive (CPE) Program CoursesRPL CPE Program ComparisonCertified Public-Safety Executive (CPE) Program FAQs CloseCourse OptionsLive ClassesCo-HostContractAgency InstructorPre- and Post-Conference Courses CloseOnline Training OptionsVirtual ClassroomAccess the Institute OnlineContinuing Dispatch Education (CDE)CDE Articles & TestsCDE CoursesActive Shooter Incidents for Public Safety CommunicationsBullying and Negativity in the Communications CenterCALEA Public Safety Communications Accreditation ManagerComprehensive QualityCrisis Negotiations for TelecommunicatorsCustomer Service in Today’s Public Safety CommunicationsCybersecurity Fundamentals for the ECCDisaster Operations and the Communications CenterFundamentals of Tactical DispatchInstructor TechniquesInstructor Techniques EnrichmentPublic Safety Communications Staffing and Employee RetentionSurviving Stress CloseIlluminations CDE ProgramsGeneral IlluminationsEMD IlluminationsCTO Illuminations CloseWebinars and RecordingsResources for Active Shooter IncidentsGuidecardsEMD GuidecardsFire Service Dispatch GuidecardsLaw Enforcement GuidecardsAPCO IntelliCommInstructorsAdjunct InstructorsAdjunct Instructor ApplicationInstructor CoursesAgency Instructor CoursesInstructor Techniques for General InstructorsInstructor Techniques Enrichment CourseCurso Para Instructores de Telecomunicación de Seguridad Pública 1 (PST) CloseBecome an Agency InstructorInstructor ResourcesContact the InstituteSchedule & RegistrationRecertificationScholarshipsFAQsOrder FormsTraining CentralComm Center Training ProgramsAPCO Training Program CertificationAPCO Training Program Certification FAQsCertified AgenciesCALEA and APCOTraining Standards & GuidelinesCursos en EspañolTelecomunicador de Seguridad PúblicaInstructores de Telecomunicación de Seguridad Pública CloseStandardsStandards to DownloadAPCO Standards Activities In ProgressHow to Assist With Standards DevelopmentJoin a Working GroupJoin a Standards Development Committee CloseStandards Review & CommentSDC Policies and ProceduresP25 Radio Interoperability CloseSpectrum ManagementFile ApplicationHave APCO Prepare Form 601 for YouPrepare FCC Form 601 Yourself Via SpectrumwatchApplication Status RequestFrequency CoordinationAFC Coordination Fee ScheduleLicensing ServiceLicensing Services FormsRenewal Request FormRequest for Buildout NotificationTermination Pending – PleadingLicensing Service WorksheetLicense Preparation Fee ScheduleLicense ManagementLicense Management Informational PacketLicense Management Fee SchedulesEngineeringEngineering Services Fee ScheduleEngineering Services Request FormEngineering ToolsMicrowave Radio SystemsMicrowave Services Request FormLocal Frequency AdvisorsLocal Advisor Interactive MapList of Local AdvisorsFor Local Advisors OnlyAFC Staff Contact InformationSpectrum Management ResourcesArticles and WebinarsSpectrumWhat is Spectrum?Spectrum Allocation Chart4.9 GHz421-430 MHzLow Power (450-470 MHz)470-512 MHz TV-Band700 MHz700 MHz Resources700 MHz Band Plan700 MHz RPC Directory Close800 MHz800 MHz Rebanding800 MHz RPC Directory800 MHz Expansion Band Considerations CloseVHF Low BandState Police Low-Band Geographical Assignment Plan Close700/800 MHz RPCInteroperabilityInteroperability Resources / SIECsInteroperability Channels CloseProject 25P25 Organizational OverviewP25 Committees, Programs & GroupsP25 ResourcesP25 Support Procedure CloseLicensingFour Steps to a Successful LicenseFCC LinksEmission Designator ListTIN Registration With FCC CloseInterferenceCompliance Request ReportCommercial Interference to 800 MHz Public Safety Licensees CloseBorder Spectrum IssuesBroadband Technology CloseMembershipJoin APCOPublic Safety Practitioner MembershipIndividual MembershipGroup MembershipWhat Is My Membership Worth?Compare Individual and Group MembershipsSea parte de algo más grandeCommercial MembershipCommercial Individual MembershipCommercial Group MembershipCompare Individual and Group MembershipsChaptersChapter PresidentsChapter Officer ToolkitCommittees and TaskforcesCommittee Sign-upRenew Your MembershipPSC MagazinePSC News WebsiteAPCO StoreMember DirectoryRecognitionLife MembersSenior MembersAPCO Walk of HeroesTeammates in ActionLeaders DinnerAwardsAwards of DistinctionPublic Safety Communications Awards Program2020 PSAP Award Winners and Nominees2019 PSAP Award Winners and NomineesTechnology Leadership AwardCommercial CommunityCommercial Advisory Council (CAC)Commercial Advisory Council MembersCommercial Advisory Council (CAC) NominationsCAC Scholarship DonationsCommercial OpportunitiesOportunidades ComercialesCorporate Partner ProgramCorporate Partner BenefitsSea parte de algo más grandeOportunidades ComercialesCursos en Español CloseEventsAPCO Annual Conference & ExpoEmerging Technology ForumLeadership in Policy Awards DinnerNational Public Safety Telecommunicators WeekNexusIndustry Events CloseComm Center/9-1-19-1-1Information on COVID-19 for Emergency Communications Centers9-1-1 Public Information and EducationPublic Information About 9-1-1About Wireless 9-1-1 CallsPublic Education Tools for TelecommunicatorsAPCO Wireless 9-1-1 Call CardsPublic Safety Telecommunicators’ Code of Ethics CloseAPCO Consulting Services (ACS)ACS Pre-Consolidation ServicesACS Review Services CloseLocation AccuracyProject LOCATE OverviewProject Locate Final ReportTop Tips for Successful Wireless DeploymentWireless Deployment Tool Kit Close CloseConsiderations for App DevelopersTERT9-1-1 TimelineNext Generation 9-1-1NG9-1-1 FirstNetInterim Text-to-911Video Relay ServiceNG9-1-1 VoIP and SIP TrunkingCareer ServicesAPCO Executive SearchProfessional Resume ReviewCareer CenterHR, Staffing & RetentionProject RETAINSAPCO Project RETAINS ToolkitRETAINS Frequently Asked QuestionsProfessional Communications Human Resources Committee (ProCHRT)ProCHRT ReportsProCHRT ToolboxAbout the ToolboxPersonnel and Recognition ResourcesTraining/Certification/Standards ResourcesPublic Education/Media RelationsHealth and WellnessLegislative ResourcesPublic Safety Communication Resources CloseInteroperabilityASAP to PSAPASAP to PSAP BackgroundASAP to PSAP ProtocolASAP FAQsASAP Resources CloseIEPD and XML SchemaUnified CAD Project (UCADS)UCAD Functional RequirementsTelematicsAACN/VEDSAACN/VEDS ResourcesVEDS Schema and Supporting Documentation CloseProject 43: Broadband Implications for the PSAPProject 43: Executive SummaryProject 43 Recommendations: OperationsProject 43 Recommendations: GovernanceProject 43 Recommendations: CybersecurityProject 43 Recommendations: TechnologyProject 43 Recommendations: TrainingProject 43 Recommendations: WorkforceConclusion and Next StepsAcknowledgements: Project 43 ContributorsImportant External ResourcesPipeline Emergency Response CloseCybersecurityAPCO Cybersecurity ResourcesFederal Cybersecurity ResourcesAdditional Cybersecurity Resources Close
APCO International Privacy Policy for Data Usage
This online privacy policy is designed to tell you about how APCO International (APCO) collects and uses personal information so that you may make an informed decision about using this website or related sites (Sites):
www.apcointl.org
psc.apcointl.org
www.psconnect.org
psc.apcointl.org
afc.apcointl.org
www.npstw.org
[Scroll to the bottom of this policy for other event-related sites open for portions of the year.]
Information Collection
When you submit a form, login, make a transaction or similar, we will only ask for personal data that is necessary for us to respond to your request.  In the course of serving our members and customers, APCO collects some basic personal information from you, including your name, email, phone number, organizational affiliation and postal address.  We may also collect payment and financial information when necessary to process an order or purchase you make.
Use of Cookies and Log Files
Like many web sites, our Sites set and use cookies to enhance your user experience, such as retaining your personal settings. By using our Sites, you consent to the use of cookies and log files.
APCO uses the information we receive from cookies and other locally stored data to enhance your experience with APCO's websites, better understand your user preferences and interactions with our websites, and to generally improve the safety and functionality of our websites and the services they provide.
In addition to our own cookies, we may also use various third-parties’ cookies to report usage statistics of the Sites, deliver advertisements on and through the service, and so on.
You can control and/or delete cookies as you wish – for details, see aboutcookies.org. You can delete all cookies that are already on your computer and you can set most browsers to prevent them from being placed. If you do this, however, you may have to manually adjust some preferences every time you visit a site and some services and functionalities may not work.
Use of Personal Data
APCO uses the personal data it collects to provide you with the service that you have requested, or to respond to an inquiry that you have made.  In serving our members and customers, we use your personal data to create registration records, course completion records, and membership and association service records.  For instance, APCO uses your data to create a verifiable record of:
participation in events, webinars, and classes;
certifications and continuing education credits;
membership and participation on association committees or standards working groups; and
service in APCO leadership roles.
All of this personal data is retained as part of your professional record with APCO as a means to demonstrate your engagement in the profession, support your career advancement and validate your eligibility for association honors such as senior and life member.
APCO may use personal data to determine user interests, needs and preferences, to conduct research and analysis, to manage and maintain the Sites and our services, to comply with our legal and compliance obligations, to exercise and defend our legal rights, or to comply with court orders.
We will also use the information to communicate with you by email about APCO events, news, and important bulletins.  APCO may also use personal information for marketing purposes and will obtain your consent for such purpose for users located in the European Union / European Economic Area.
Data Retention
APCO retains personal data for so long as it is necessary for us to comply with our legitimate business requirements, to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, to protect our assets, to provide services that you have requested, and to enforce our agreements.
Disclosures of Personal Data
APCO may share your personal information with select business partners for marketing and research purposes. APCO may also share your personal information with third party service providers who assist us in providing the Sites and our services to you.  Our third party service providers are bound to keep your personal information confidential.
Hyperlinks
The Sites contain links to other websites, including without limitation those websites of companies identified as official vendors or sponsors. Their inclusion does not imply any endorsement or validation by us of the content of said websites. APCO International is not responsible for the privacy practices of such third party websites, nor do we accept any liability in connection with the content of such websites.
Security of Personal Data
APCO is committed to keeping your data safe.  As part of our business operations we maintain appropriate security measures to prevent security breaches and unauthorized disclosure of client data.  Any financial data requested and transmitted through our Sites are transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets a web browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before it is sent to us. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or data storage is 100% secure. Since no data security measures are foolproof, we cannot guarantee the security of data transmitted or stored via our software and systems.
Global Users
APCO is located and established in the United States and therefore, your personal information may be transferred to, stored or processed in the United States.  While the data protection, privacy and other laws of the United States may not be as comprehensive as those in your country, we take necessary and appropriate steps to protect the security and privacy of your personal information.  By using the Sites or requesting services from us, you understand and consent to the collection, storage, processing and transfer of your personal data to our facilities in the United States and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Policy.
Your Rights to Access and Control Your Information
You have the right to review and request a copy of the personal data that we store about you, if any.  You also have the right to change or correct any data we have about you, ask us to delete your personal data, or express concern you have about our use of your information.  You can review and make changes to your account profile by logging into the Sites.
You may request that we stop sending such communications at any time, and you have the right to request that APCO remove your data from our databases.  You can manage your communication preferences online. Go to www.myapcointl.org and click on “Manage Correspondence” in the right corner. All of our email communications contain an unsubscribe link.  If you wish to stop receiving a particular communication from us, you will be able to do so by following the unsubscribe link in our emails.  If you wish to have your data deleted from all records, please be advised that this may affect your membership, training, certification, or eligibility for honors status.  However, should you wish to have your information purged from APCO data or if you have other requests, please email us (data@apcointl.org).  We will seek to accommodate your requests, including requests for deletion, as required by applicable law.
Changes/Updates to Privacy Policy
In order to keep up with changing legislation and best practices, we may revise this privacy policy at any time without notice. Please check back periodically so that you are aware of any changes.
Contact Us
If you have any questions about this privacy policy or feel that your privacy has been compromised, please contact us marketing@apcointl.org or alternatively:
APCO International
1426 Prince St
Alexandria, VA 22314
Please note these other APCO-related sites not listed at the top of this policy:
www.apco2019.org
www.apco2020.ofb
techforum.apcointl.org
broadbandsummit.apcointl.org
leadersdinner.apcointl.org
www.apcoenvision.org
www.apconexus.org
[Updated 5/24/2018]
About
Government Relations
Training & Certification
Standards
Spectrum Management
Membership
Events
Comm Center & 9-1-1
Report Website Errors
All material © 2020 APCO International, Inc. All Rights Reserved
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use this site we will assume that you are happy with it.Ok
